Welcome back, In this video we're going to talk about converting regular expressions
欢迎回来，在这段视频中，我们将讨论如何转换正则表达式
into non-deterministic finite automata. Before we get started I wanna give you an
变成非确定的有限自动机。在我们开始之前，我想给你们一个
overview of the plan for the next few videos. We have a lexical specification
接下来几个视频的计划概述。我们有一个词汇说明
that we want to implement and the first step is for someone to write that down as
我们想要实现，第一步是有人把它写成
a set of regular expressions. Now that bites all the courses not implementation,
一组正则表达式。既然这会影响到所有的课程而不是实施，
that's just specification. So we have to translate that into a program that can
那只是说明书而已。所以我们必须把它转化成一个可以
actually do lexical analysis and this actually happens in several steps. The
实际上是做词法分析，这实际上是分几步进行的。这个
first part is a translate Those regular expressions into non-deterministic finite
第一部分是将这些正则表达式转换为非确定性有限表达式。
automata that recognize the same, exactly the same thing. And then those
能够识别相同的、完全相同的东西的自动机。然后是那些
non-deterministic automata are translated into deterministic automata and finally
将非确定自动机转化为确定自动机，最后
those deterministic automata are implemented as a set of Lookup tables and
这些确定性自动机被实现为一组查找表，并且
a little bit of code for traversing those tables. So in previous videos, we talked
一些用于遍历这些表的代码。所以在之前的视频中，我们谈到
about this piece and we've also defined this piece. And so now we're ready to put
关于这件事，我们也给这件事下了定义。所以现在我们准备好把
the whole thing together and in this particular video, we're going to focus on
在这段特别的视频中，我们将把整个事情放在一起，重点放在
this component right here, The translation of regular expressions to
这个组件就在这里，将正则表达式转换为
non-deterministic finite automata. So the plan is that for each kind of regular
非确定性有限自动机。所以我们的计划是，对于每一种常规的
expression we're going to find an equivalent Non-deterministic Automata,
表达式，我们将找到一个等价的非确定自动机，
automaton that accepts exactly the same language as the language or a regular
接受与语言或常规语言完全相同的语言的自动机
expression. And here's a little bit of notation we're gonna use. We'll define
表达式。这是我们要用到的一点符号。我们会定义
these automaton for regular expressions and usually, what we're going to be doing
这些正则表达式的自动机，通常情况下，我们要做的是
is needing to modify their start states and their final states so we'll just
需要修改它们的开始状态和最终状态，所以我们只需
indicate the start state with the l and the final state. With the double circle
用l和最终状态指示开始状态。用双圆圈
and we won't worry too much about the overall structure of the machine as long
而且我们也不会太担心机器的整体结构，只要
as we have a handle on the start state and the final state. I should say that in the
因为我们掌握了开始状态和最终状态的句柄。我应该说，在
machines we'll build here, there will only be one final state. Okay, so let's begin.
我们在这里建造的机器，只有一个最终状态。好的，我们开始吧。
So for the epsilon regular expression, once the machine that accepts that, well
所以对于epsilon正则表达式，一旦机器接受了它，那么
this is a very simple machine. We can just have a start state and a final state and
这是一台非常简单的机器。我们可以只有一个开始状态和一个最终状态
epsilon transition between them so this machine accepts exactly the empty string.
Epsilon在它们之间转换，所以这台机器完全接受空字符串。
Certainly for a single character A, we can define a one transition two state machine
当然，对于单个字符A，我们可以定义一个一个转换两个状态机
that accepts that one character. So from the start state we can move to the final
它接受这一个字符。所以我们可以从开始状态进入决赛
state if it only, if we read that particular character, okay. So those are
如果我们读了那个特定的字符，请说明，好的。所以这些都是
out two simple regular expressions and now we have to do the compound regular
输出了两个简单的正则表达式，现在我们必须做复合正则表达式
expressions. And these are little [inaudible] involved. So let's talk about
表情。而且这些都很少[听不见]涉及到。所以我们来谈谈
concatenation first. And so, because we're gonna build these machines up from
先串接。所以，因为我们要把这些机器从
smaller. Regular expressions to larger ones, we can assume that we've already
小一点。正则表达式转换为更大的正则表达式，我们可以假设我们已经
converted A and B separately in two machines. So I have the machine for A. And
在两台机器中分别转换A和B。我有A和A的取款机。
to have a machine for B and now all I have to do is say how I'm going to paste
有一台机器给B，现在我要做的就是说我要怎么粘贴
together these two machines to form a machine, a compound machine that
把这两台机器放在一起组成一台机器，一台复合机，
recognizes the same language as a concatenated with B. And here's the
将相同的语言识别为与B连接的
construction, the start state for the compound machine will be the start state
构造时，复合机的启动状态将为启动状态
for A so we'll just keep that start state for A the same and then we modify the
对于A，我们只需保持A的起始状态不变，然后修改
final state of A. So we make the final state of A no longer a final state and
所以我们使A的终态不再是终态，
I've done that here by removing the double circle on the final state of A andthe
我在这里通过去掉A的最终状态上的双圆来做到这一点，并且
epsilon transition to the start state of B. Now if we think about it, that does
Epsilon转变到B的开始状态。现在，如果我们想一想，那就是
exactly the right thing but that says, is that first you recognize some portion of
这确实是正确的，但也就是说，首先你会认识到
the input that belongs to the language of A, and when we get to that, what would
属于A语言的输入，当我们谈到这一点时，
been the final state of A, we can jump to the start state of B without consuming any
作为A的最终状态，我们可以跳到B的开始状态，而不消耗任何
input and then try to read the rest of the string as part of the language, as, as a
输入，然后尝试将字符串的睡觉作为语言的一部分，作为，作为
string in the language of B. And for union we have a similar way of phasing together
B语言中的字符串。对于联合，我们有一个类似的分阶段的方法。
the machines. Although the, the structure is somewhat different so we, at a new
机器。虽然这个结构有点不一样，所以我们在一个新的
start state for the compound machine and What does A + B mean? It means either the
复合机的启动状态，A+B是什么意思？这意味着要么是
input is in the language of A, or it's in the language of B. And epsilon transitions
输入使用A的语言，或者使用B的语言。
are really good for capturing this because we just make a decision right from the
非常适合于捕捉到这一点，因为我们只是根据
start state is the string going to be in language of A or is it going to be in the
开始状态是将使用A语言的字符串，还是将使用
language of B. So we make a non-deterministic choice and then we read
所以我们做了一个非确定性的选择，然后我们读到
the string as using that, the automaton that we chose and if we get to the final
使用的字符串，我们选择的自动机，如果我们进入决赛
state. Either those machines we can make the epsilon transition to the new final
州政府。不管是那些机器，我们都可以把epsilon过渡到新的决赛
state for the compound machine. Now remember what the notion is of acceptance
复合机的状态。现在请记住接受的概念是什么
for Nondeterministic Automata, you know? They make these guesses but if there's any
不确定自动机，你知道吗？他们会做出这些猜测，但如果有
guess that works, then we say that it's in the language of the machine. So, if in
我想这是可行的，那么我们就说它是用机器的语言写的。所以，如果在
fact the string is in the union of A or B then either choosing A or choosing B will
事实上，字符串是A或B的并集，那么选择A或选择B都将
work and so the machine will accept the string. And finally the most complicated
工作，所以机器会接受绳子。最后是最复杂的
case for iteration is star, we have the following construction, So here's the
迭代的案例是STAR，我们有以下结构，所以这里是
machine for A, Embedded in here. We've added a new start state and a new final
A的机器，嵌入在这里。我们增加了一个新的起跑状态和一个新的决赛
state, And now, let's talk about how this works. So one possibility is, remember
现在，让我们来讨论一下这是如何工作的。所以一种可能性是，记住
that epsilon is always in the language of A star, and so we have this transition here,
那个ε总是用A星的语言表示的，所以我们在这里有了这个过渡，
We can go straight from the start state to the final state and accept the empty
我们可以直接从开始状态进入最终状态，并接受空的
string. And so, that just guarantees that the empty string is in the language.
字符串。因此，这只能保证空字符串在语言中。
Otherwise, what do we do? Otherwise, we can make a transition, an epsilon
否则，我们该怎么办？否则，我们可以做一个转变，一个ε
transition to the start state of A. And then we can, from the final state of A if
转换到A的开始状态，然后我们可以从A的最终状态IF
we reach it, we can go back to the start state of the whole machine and we can do
当我们到达它时，我们可以返回到整个机器的启动状态，我们可以这样做
this as many times as we like. Okay, So, there's the iteration of A, Surround this
我们想要多少次都可以。好的，这是A的迭代，围绕着这个
loop right here, And when we reach the final state of A we can also decide to
就在这里循环，当我们到达A的最终状态时，我们也可以决定
just make a transition to the final state of the machine, we conclude that the last
只要转换到机器的最终状态，我们就可以得出结论，最后一个
time. And so this machine recognizes zero or more strings in the language of A. So
时间到了。因此，这台机器可以识别零个或多个a语言的字符串。
now, let's do an example, So here's a regular expression and we want to build a
现在，让我们来做一个例子，所以这里有一个正则表达式，我们想要构建一个
equivalent nondeterministic machine that recognizes the sa me language and we're
等价的不确定机器，它可以识别简单的语言，而我们
gonna follow our construction, Which works by induction on the structure of the
我将跟随我们的建筑，通过对结构的归纳来工作
regular expressions starting with the simple regular expressions and building up
正则表达式从简单的正则表达式开始构建
to the compound one so what do we have here? So we have a machine for accepting
到院子里的那个那么我们这里有什么？所以我们有一台机器来接受
one, okay. So we need a machine that accepts one and if we call it had two
一件，好的。所以我们需要一台可以接受一台的机器，如果我们称之为有两台的话
states and it just, you know made a transition between the two on the number
它只是，你知道的，在数字上在这两个州之间做了一个转换
one, Similarly a machine for accepting zero. Okay, And now, we need to put them
第一，同样是一台接受零的机器。好的，现在，我们要把它们
together in a machine that accepts either one or zero. And the way we did that is we
一起放在一台可以接受1或0的机器里。我们做到这一点的方式是我们
made a choice from A, from a start state for the compound machine where you can
从A中进行选择，从复合机的启动状态中进行选择
either move to the machine for accepting one or the machine for accepting zero. And
要么移动到接受1的机器，要么移动到接受0的机器。和
then we have, at the end, also epsilon moves back to the final state of the
然后我们在最后，也有ε移动回最后的状态，
compound machine. Okay, And now we need to iterate this so we need to be able to
复合机。好的，现在我们需要迭代这个，所以我们需要能够
accept zero or more of one's or zero's and so we're going to take this entire Block
接受零个或多个1或0，所以我们将使用整个挡路
here and paste it into the pattern that we had for iteration so how do we do that?
并将其粘贴到我们用于迭代的模式中，那么我们如何做到这一点呢？
Well, we have a new start state and a new final state, okay. And there's an epsilon
嗯，我们有一个新的起始态和一个新的终止态，好的。还有一个ε
move from the start state to the new final state to guarantee that we accept the
从开始状态移动到新的最终状态，以保证我们接受
empty string. And then we can just iterate this inner machine as many times as we
空字符串。然后我们就可以把这台内部机器重复尽可能多的次数
like. We can make an epsilon move to the start state, We could execute the machine
喜欢。我们可以使epsilon移动到启动状态，我们可以执行机器
ones and if we decide we want to do it again, well we can do that. Okay, Go back
如果我们决定再来一次，我们可以这么做。好的，回去吧
around for another time, Or from the final state, we can decide that we've seen
在另一个时间，或者从最终的状态，我们可以决定我们已经看到
enough and we can just move to the final state of the compound machine. So this
够了，我们就可以转到复合机的最终状态了。所以这件事
machine then accepts the language one + zero'lt;i>. And now, we have a little bit more'lt;/i>
然后，机器接受语言1+0‘lt；i>。现在，我们有更多的‘lt；/i>
to do. We have to accept, we have other machine that accepts just one so we build
去做。我们必须接受，我们有另一台机器只接受一台，所以我们构建
another machine that accepts The digit one and now we need to compose two of these
另一台接受数字1的机器，现在我们需要组合其中的两台
things, to concatenate them and that was very simple. We just have an epsilon move
将它们连接起来，这是非常简单的。我们刚刚有了一个埃西隆动作
from the final state of the first machine to the start state of the second mac hine
从第一机器的最终状态到第二Mac Hine的启动状态
and then these are all the states of the final machine. And we just need to now
然后这些就是最终机器的所有状态。我们现在只需要
label our final, final state or the end of the state that we're actually gonna use in
将我们实际要使用的最终状态或状态的结束标记为
the end of the final state of the entire machine which should be that one and the
整个计算机的最终状态(应该是该状态)的末尾，并且
start state, Which is this state over here. And that's the entire construction
开始状态，这就是这里的状态。这就是整个建筑
for the non-deterministic automata or a non-deterministic automata that recognizes
对于非确定自动机或识别的非确定自动机
this language.
这种语言。